Yunfei Luo

Ph.D. Student in the Halicioğlu Data Science Institute at the University of California San Diego

□ (413) 404 2124 ② yul268@ucsd.edu ♀ San Diego, CA yunfeiluo.github.io in linkedin.com/in/yunfei-luo ♀ github.com/yunfeiluo

Yunfei's research focuses on applied machine learning in the field of ubiquitous health, modeling with multimodal data including wearable sensing signal electronic health records. He aim to develop robust and well generalized methodology that could enhance the intelligent monitoring, intervention, and be able to be deployed on edge devices.

Education

09.2023 - present Ph.D. Student in the Halıcıoğlu Data Science Institute

University of California, San Diego, CA

- > Advisor : Tauhidur Rahman
- > Research: Applied Machine Learning, Multimodal Learning, Multitask Learning, Digital Health

09.2021 - 05.2023 Master of Science in Computer Science

GPA: 3.92/4.0 University of Massachusetts Amherst, Amherst, MA

- > Advisor : Ina Fiterau Brostean | ☑ Information Fusion Lab
- > Courses Taken: Advanced Machine Learning, Neural Networks, Probabilistic Graphical Models, Reinforcement Learning, Advanced Natural Language Processing, Advanced IoT

09.2017 - 05.2021 Bachelor of Science in Computer Science | Bachelor of Science in Mathematics

GPA: 3.84/4.0 University of Massachusetts Amherst, Amherst, MA

> Machine Learning and Computing Specializations

Fellowships, Scholarships, Awards, and Honors

2021 - 2023 Bay State Fellowship | Full Tuition Scholarship

2017 - 2021 Outstanding Undergraduate Course Assistant Award Chancellor's Award, UMass Amherst

Publications

Real Time Intradialytic Hypotension Forecasting Leveraging Modern Deep Learning Method with Fusion of Physiological Data and Electronic Health Record, TBD, Journal

Preparing

Yunfei Luo, Siwei Zhao, Rakesh Malhotra, Tauhidur Rahman, Subhasis Dasgupta

> Novel multimodal modeling on physiological data, dialysis machine parameter, and electronic health records. Aiming to accurately forecasting hypotension 1 hour ahead in dialysis patient, and to provide comprehensive insights to nurse for intervention recommendation.

Signal Processing Nephrology Clinical Treatment Machine Learning Multimodal Fusion Ubiquitous Health

Opioid Misuse Risk Modeling with Semantic Representation of Health Record and Nonlinear Dynamics of Personalized Inferential Affective State Trajectories from Wearable Data, TBD, Journal

Preparing

Yunfei Luo, Iman Deznabi, Bhanu Gullapalli, Katrin Haensel, Mark Tuomenoksa, Eric Garland, Madalina Fiterau, Tauhidur Rahman

- > Leveraging transformer based time series model and dynamic branching to predict the stress, pain, and craving of Opioid users based on heart beat data collected from wearable sensor.
- > Leveraging topological features from trajectory of inferential affective states across days and natural language processing technique to predict the risk of having opioid misuse behavior.

Signal Processing | Heart Rate Variability | Affective States | Opioid | Clinical Treatment | Machine Learning | Multimodal Fusion | Ubiquitous Health |

2024 Dynamic Clustering via Branched Deep Learning Enhances Personalization of Stress Prediction from Mobile Sensor Data, Nature Scientific Report, Journal

Accepted

Yunfei Luo, Iman Deznabi, Abhinav Shaw, Tauhidur Rahman, Madalina Fiterau Brostean

- > Proposed a novel approach to modeling the Multimodal data, got results that outperform SOTA
- > Modeled personalized and populational characteristics with Multitask Learning and Dynamic Clustering Method respectively
- > Evaluated the performance under cold-start setting, to support the robustness of our method Multi-modal | Fusion Methods | Mental Health | Machine Learning | Neural Networks | Time Series

2024 Accepted

Start Simple: Progressive Difficulty Multitask Learning, NAACL 2024 SRW Proceedings, Conference Yunfei Luo, Yuyang Liu, Rukai Cai, Tauhidur Rahman

> Introducing sub-tasks with progressive difficulties to improve the performance on main task. Inspired by how people learn. Experimented on text classification, sentiment analysis, and argument mining Natural Language Processing | Multi-task Learning | Machine Learning | Neural Networks

2023

Agent Performing Autonomous Stock Trading under Good and Bad Situations, Al for Agent-Based Modelling (AI4ABM) in International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), Workshop Yunfei Luo, Zhangqi Duan

Accepted

> Researched and experimented with different reinforcement learning algorithms to train agents to perform stock trading. The methods are evaluated under scenarios with stable and non-stable market Natural Language Processing | Multi-task Learning | Machine Learning | Neural Networks



Professional Experience

Summer 2022 to 06.2023

Machine Learning Engineering Intern, Center for Data Science, UMass Amherst

- > Developed platform for Building Segmentation and Damage Assessment based on Satellite Imagery
- > Integrated the Machine Learning pipeline along with User Interface for Imagery Fetching and Labelling
- > Conducted Research and Experiments with various Finetuning setting and Machine Learning techniques to support selections of final-deployed hyper-parameters and models
- > Worked as Research Assistant after internship

Computer Vision | Machine Learning | Disaster Response | Software Development | Full-Stack Development

Summer 2020 to 06.2021

Data Engineering Intern, Institute for Applied Life Sciences, UMass Amherst

- > Built pipelines for fMRI data preprocessing and statistical analysis
- > Conducted Research and Experiments with Machine Learning models for Stroke Detection : Autoencoders, CNNs, and GANs
- > Worked as Undergraduate Research Assistant after internship

Machine Learning | fMRI | Data Preparation



Teaching Experience

Fall 2021 to Spring 2023

Graduate Teachinge Assistant, CICS, UMass Amherst

- > CS 311 Introduction to Algorithm in Fall 2021 and Spring 2023
- > CS 5900P Applied Numerical Optimization, and CS 108 Foundation of Data Science in Fall 2022
- > CS 220 Programming Methodology in Spring 2022
- > Held office hours, led weekly discussion sessions, graded course works, answered questions on course forum, attended weekly TA meeting for discussing the progress/improvements of the course Javascript Algorithms Numerical Optimization Data Science Teaching

Spring 2020 to Spring 2021

Undergraduate Course Assistant, CICS, UMass Amherst

- > CS 240 Reasoning under Uncertainty in Spring 2021, CS 311 Introduction to Algorithms in Fall 2020, CS 220 Programming Methodology in Spring 2020
- > Helped with weekly discussion session, graded course works, and answered questions on Piazza Javascript Algorithms Probability Teaching

Professional Certifications

- 2022 IBM Artificial Intelligence Engineering Professional Certificate
- 2022 Neuroscience and Neuroimaging Specialization Certificate
- 2020 TensorFlow Developer Professional Certificate

66 References

Tauhidur Rahman

Assistant Professor of Computer Science University of California San Diego Co-Director of MOSAIC Lab

@ trahman@ucsd.edu

Tom Bernardin

Data Scientist University of Massachusetts Amherst Director of the Center for Data Science

@ tbernard@cs.umass.edu

Madalina Fiterau Brostean

Assistant Professor of Computer Science University of Massachusetts Amherst Lead of the Information Fusion Lab

@ mfiterau@cs.umass.edu

Daniel Sheldon

Associate Professor of Computer Science University of Massachusetts Amherst College of Information and Computer Science

@ sheldon@cs.umass.edu

Subhransu Maji

Associate Professor of Computer Science University of Massachusetts Amherst Co-Director of Computer Vision Lab

@ smaji@cs.umass.edu